[♪ opening theme song playing]
DAEMONS OF THE SHADOW REALM
[blows]
All right, that should do it.
Wow, so cool.
You make all of your weapons
and stuff yourself?
Yeah, I can pretty much
make everything
that I need to survive.
I learned most of it
from my dad.
Figured out the rest myself.
At that point, I was on my own.
I'd like to find someplace
I can try it out.
Yuru, do you think you could
teach me how to use a weapon?
[YURU] Mm?
[KEN] I want to get stronger.
♪
[Ken sighs]
[YURU] Sure.
I can do that.
EPISODE 12
RETAINER AND SHAMAN
[birds chirping]
[TACHIKAWA] Hello.
[Akai and Midori whining]
[GABBY AND ASA] Uh?
[TACHIKAWA] Hm?
Oh, hey, it's you.
Sorry, uh...
The name's Makoto.
Makoto Tachikawa.
It's nice seeing you again.
Of course, I remember now.
Nice to see you.
Great, the chick
with the woodland creatures.
[ASA] So are you working today?
[TACHIKAWA] Yep.
Jin asked me to come in.
[ASA] And hello to you, too,
Akai and Midori.
[Akai and Midori grunt]
By the way,
what are their abilities?
We haven't seen them
in action yet.
They're good at kidnappings
and abductions.
That sort of thing.
Isn't that Yin-Yang's
specialty, too?
Hiding people and then
spitting them back out again?
[Daifuku and Ohagi scream]
Oh, I see.
And the point of the raid
was to kidnap me and Yuru,
so it makes sense
you'd be recruited for it.
So how do your daemons
do their snatching, Mako?
A nickname, that's fun.
Well, Akai can transform
into a person,
so we use that ability
to honey trap our targets.
As for Midori,
well, they say tanuki
are as broad
as eight tatami mats.
They stretch out a ton,
kinda like a giant net.
Then they can instantly envelop
someone to kidnap them.
[ASA AND GABBY]
They use their eight-mat
to envelop and kidnap people.
Pure evil.
In fact, the little guy
actually fought
in the legendary
Shikoku tanuki war.
[GABBY] Can you imagine
being abducted
by a tanuki nut sack?
That's like nightmare fuel.
[ASA] Thank you so much
for kidnapping me
before Midori could, Yin-Yang.
I owe you guys.
[GABBY] Midori may be
the most terrifying daemon ever.
So, Jin, what is this work
that you summoned Tachikawa here
to take care of today?
You wouldn't be planning
to use Midori
to kidnap my brother,
now would you?
No, of course not.
She came to help us solve
the mystery
of the non-existent west gate.
Okay, weird.
There was definitely a gate
in that wall before.
I remember the spot.
Everything else is still here.
That big rock
and the fruit trees.
Which means the gate
should be right over there.
I'm absolutely sure.
So where the heck did it go?
Sensei's daemons
can rewrite reality.
We would know
if it had been him, though.
The changes he makes
always take a while
to blend in
with their surroundings.
[JIN] Hm.
♪
There actually are faint lines
visible here.
[ALL] Hm?
[ASA] Where?
Wait.
I can see it.
Like a clean cut.
[ASA] Uh?
And another one!
Well, folks...
Don't know about you,
but it looks like a gate to me.
It wasn't made
by a simple razor. No way.
It had to have been
much sharper.
[beeping]
[FEMALE ASSISTANT]
Mr. Shingo, you have a guest
at the front desk.
[SHINGO] All right,
you can send him up.
[knocking on door]
[EMPLOYEE] Your guest, sir.
Uncle, hello!
Hello, Asuma. You look well.
I am, thank you.
Sorry for always making you
come to me.
Not very considerate, huh?
If that's how you really feel,
it would be
simple enough to fix.
You could visit the manor
instead of asking me
to come here.
Yeah, not gonna happen.
Don't need Fuyuki's Blacklist
reciting all my personal info.
Too risky.
Go in there unarmed
and daemon-less?
You won't catch me
doin' that in a million years.
No one would attack you
if you were unarmed,
I assure you.
[SHINGO]
Any other updates to share?
[ASUMA] No, none.
As I told you,
Asa stayed with us,
and Yuru went with Tadera.
How could you let the Seal kid
walk out the door?
Huh?
Asuma...
Quit wasting time
and make a move, boy.
You had a golden opportunity
to capture one of the twins,
and instead of seizing it,
you just sat on your ass
and watched.
Yuru may be young,
but he and his daemons
aren't easily beaten, Uncle.
You would have
seen that for yourself
if you had only been there.
[Shingo grunting softly]
Get rid of that mangaka.
Make him disappear,
and the clan will be yours.
Even if something
did happen to Hagure,
I doubt the current head
of the clan
would conveniently drop dead.
If brute force isn't gonna work,
then win over Asa instead.
She's a naive little thing,
after all.
Just sweet talk her.
Make the girl yours.
I'm sure you know it's a crime
for an adult to make advances
on a sixteen-year-old.
You some sort of square?
[scoffs] I see you're every bit
as useless as your mother.
♪
[ASUMA] Since I've nothing else
to report, I'll be going now.
I'll show myself out.
I meant what I said.
You should come
visit the manor sometime.
-Give it a rest.
-[door opens]
[door closes]
[toilet flushes]
[IVAN] Oh. Did your nephew
leave already?
Yeah.
I forgot to tell him
that you had dropped by.
Whatever, I'm sure
you'll see him soon enough.
[Ivan sighs] I hate to say it.
Somebody ought to have
trained the boy better.
If you let your guard down
just because someone's family,
you're asking for trouble.
[keyboard clacking]
[HANA] Taking care
of one kid is hard enough.
Two'll be even worse.
You sure this is a good idea?
It'll be fine, don't worry.
That kid...
He's got his shit together.
Just look at what he did
after freeing Tenaga-Ashinaga.
He knew he had screwed up,
and he was willing
to risk himself to fix it.
-He's sharp, too.
-Oh! What is this?
[DERA] I bet he'll end up
being more of an asset
-than you'd expect.
-A god of the wind held captive?
He's a good egg.
I can tell, you know.
Yeah, well, trying hard
to be good all the time
can take a toll on a kid.
The effort of doing so
slowly starts wearing
their hearts out after a while.
Uh? Jackpot.
I think this is it.
What is?
A government database
of missing persons.
They've got a whole bunch
of info on here,
like the last day
a missing person
was seen, you know?
So I've just been researching
and digging back
through the Tohoku records
from before Yuru was born.
Kinjo Nagisa.
[Yuru gasps]
[HANA]
Hiking registration form
found at the
Old Higashi Village Trailhead.
[DERA] The date
and age both match.
It doesn't look like
her address is listed, though.
You mean my mom?
Yeah, right? I'm thinking
that this must be her.
Back at the manor,
they told me that
my mom was from Okinawa.
That would make sense.
Kinjo is a common name there.
Here, this is how
you write Okinawa.
KINJO NAGISA
OKINAWA
They said Nagisa vanished
while on a journey
to visit her parents,
did they not?
Yeah.
[HANA] Which means we've got
a good idea
of where your grandparents live.
[Yuru breathes uneasily]
[both grunting]
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
I had Ryu Tadera tailed
and was able to locate
his hideout.
What did you do that for?
That's exactly the kind of move
we were avoiding.
We're attempting to earn
the brother's trust here.
They'll think
it was a clan decision,
and we'll be back to square one.
[ASUMA] As we thought,
it was a type of barrier.
One called a Lost House.
One of the people
I sent returned,
but two never will.
So they've gone missing
like the others?
No, they're dead.
We can be certain of that.
They were aged 19 and 40.
Both were single men
and neither of them
had any friends
or family to speak of.
[JIN] Hmm.
We can use their identities,
so I'll leave them
as officially alive
in their family registers.
It's a shame, really.
If the 19-year-old
who died had been a woman,
Gabby could have used
their identity.
Her or Asa.
Deceased 16-year-old girls
without any close relations
are difficult to come by.
Let alone finding two of them.
Gabby seems to be fine
with things the way
they are for now.
And Asa can be rather stubborn.
I doubt she would agree to claim
someone's identity as her own.
[phone ringing]
Yes. Hello?
[GABBY] You at the manor, Jinny?
Asa got a call from someone.
Her gran in Okinawa.
Oh, I'm doing great.
Yes. I'm so happy
that you've been well, too.
I promise, the Kagemoris
are taking good care of me.
Yes.
No, I'm sorry.
I wish I could tell you,
but I still don't know
where Mom and Dad are.
[GRANDMA KINJO] I see.
KINJO
As long as it's been,
I keep expecting Nagisa
to turn up
out of the blue someday.
Truth is,
I'm getting old and the years
are starting to catch up to me.
And as much as I would love
to see Nagisa again,
what I want more than anything
is to meet you.
[Asa gasps]
[GRANDMA KINJO] Please, dear,
you're my granddaughter.
I'd like to see you once
before my health fails me
and I lose the chance for good.
[ASA] I'm really sorry, Grandma.
I can't come visit you yet.
I would just cause trouble
for you.
Yeah. I'm glad
I got to hear your voice.
Hope we'll chat again soon.
Love you.
No change.
She was the same as always.
[JIN] Hmm.
Every single word and phrase
was exactly the same.
KINJO
I'd like to see you once
before my health fails me
and I lose the chance for good.
Please, dear,
you're my granddaughter.
I'd like to see you once
before my health fails me
and I lose the chance for good.
I'd like to see you.
[Asa inhales, sighs]
[Daifuku and Ohagi whine]
[chuckles] Hey, it's okay.
I'm okay.
[GABBY] Scumbags.
DAEMONS OF THE SHADOW REALM
So, next,
can we find these Kinjos
so that we can learn
about my mom?
Do you have any idea
how many Kinjos there are
in Okinawa?
It's gotta be at least
the second most common surname
they've got.
Think with me here.
Nagisa went missing while trying
to pay them a visit.
We wouldn't want to draw
any more attention
to her family out there.
They've been through a lot.
Don't need to put 'em
in danger, too.
[YURU] Hm.
For all we know,
it's too late for old Kinjo.
And someone might
already be there
with a trap set for us.
The Kagemori family
offered to protect Nagisa.
I'm sure they know which Kinjos
are the ones related to her.
With how secretive
the Kagemoris are,
if they haven't taken that part
of the family under their wing,
well, it doesn't look good.
[Yuru breathes uneasily]
[Dera sighs]
Guess the old Tadera clan head
is our best lead after all.
I'm gonna see the shaman.
[KEN] Huh?
♪
PRAYERS - EXORCISMS
SPIRITUAL HEALING
Anyone in here?
Please, come on in!
How nice to get
an afternoon visit
from you like this!
I've got no more customers,
so close on up!
[DERA] I got it.
How was your village trip?
Like usual? Peaceful?
[DERA] Yeah.
Actually, about that...
Little Azami from the village
will be turning seven soon.
So, it's time.
[YAMA] Oh, yes.
She's about ready to get her
vaccinations, isn't she?
So, you just need
measles and rubella?
I'll get them prepped for her.
Also, the village is a wreck
after a Kagemori attack.
Talk about burying
the lead, there!
Don't tack that on
like an afterthought
to a kid's vaccination!
That's why you're really here!
Gotta have your appetizer before
the main course is served.
[YAMA] Oh, I guess.
[DERA] So, let's talk.
I'm sure you've heard,
but one of the twins
is with the Kagemoris.
-[DERA] Hm? [chuckles]
-[YAMA] Yeah. They have Asa.
She acquired the power of Break
and used it to bust straight
through Higashi's barrier.
She brought
the Kagemoris with her.
[gasps] What about Yuru?
They didn't take him, right?
Calm down.
I'm lookin' after
the kid myself.
Granny told me
to take him and escape.
He's livin' down here.
[Yama groans softly]
We might've gotten
into a little scuffle
with some of the Kagemoris
as we were getting off
the mountain.
But we did eventually lose them.
Oh, please, no more!
We can't let another twin
fall into someone else's hands!
Just no!
And you're sure it was
the power of Break?
[DERA] No doubt about it.
Even said she got it
after she died once.
[Yama chuckles]
And here I was,
thinking Break and Seal
were nothing
but the delusions
of the last generation!
Well, anyway.
I'm not sure I can really
protect him by myself.
I'd love a chance to pick
my predecessor's brain,
only I've got no clue
where he could be.
You still haven't been able
to get in touch?
That must be hard for you.
[DERA] It's been 10 years!
Haven't heard squat from him.
Any chance you have?
[YAMA] I'm afraid
I'm no better off
than you are on that one.
I'm sure somebody'll
find him off
in some ditch somewhere.
I could always ask around.
Want me to see if our
Higashi contacts have a lead?
[Dera sighs]
Please and thank you!
[YAMA] Hmm...
So, where are you hiding Yuru
now that he's in your care?
I got a secret second pad.
♪
Oh, good.
I'm sure he's safe there.
[DERA] I don't know.
I swear the kid's blood burns
hotter than the sun.
He knows how to talk a big game.
He said if anyone wants
his head,
they should come and get it.
That after he beats them
black and blue,
he'll squeeze out their info.
[Yama sighs] Sounds like
he's looking for a fight!
[DERA] Yeah, it sucks!
Wish he'd try putting himself
in my shoes!
[chuckles] Anyway.
I've got my hands full
dealin' with that for a while,
so no chance I'll be able
to head up to the village.
[YAMA] Oh, I get it.
Well, maybe I'll check in
on the townsfolk
while I'm there
for Azami's "exorcism."
[DERA] Appreciate it.
Lot of folks are beaten up
real bad.
Make sure you bring
some medicine.
Oh, maybe that's why.
♪
[YAMA] Last night,
I was accosted by a strange man!
He had some katanas.
Well, considering there were
two of them,
they must've been daemons.
Probably.
And in a flash,
he closed the distance.
[Yama and Tsugais yell]
[Tsugais squealing]
-[DERA] Did he cut you?
-[YAMA] No.
When I came to,
I was lying in the street.
I didn't have a scratch on me.
At the time, I thought he was
some pervert.
Still could be!
But now, I have my doubts.
I wonder if he was after Yuru.
So, a pair of katanas.
Hmm. I'll keep an eye out.
If you do find out
something about my predecessor,
-I wanna be the first to know.
-Sure thing!
And don't get tailed
into the village, Mr. Shaman.
Be careful.
[scoffs] No need to worry.
-I always am.
-[door closes]
[bird cawing]
[YAMA] Oh, dear!
No, no, no.
This is simply terrible!
Signs of mourning
everywhere you look.
-[BOY 1] It's the shaman!
-[Yama gasps]
[BOY 2] Mr. Yama!
[YAMA] Oh, my darling munchkins!
You're all all right!
[BOY 1] It was awful!
Some strangers came
and killed people, Mr. Yama!
Dera already let me know.
They had iron birds
and iron shooty-ball things,
too!
It was so scary. And loud!
And look way over there!
Left and Right are gone!
[BOY 2] I think an evil god
must've come to the village!
What's happening?
Are Left and Right broken?
The strangers had
some invisible power.
They were cutting a bunch
of grown-ups in half so easily.
[YAMA] Hmm...
They killed Azami's Ma
in front of her.
'Kay...
Get ready
to feel the god!
Hold still.
There might be a little pinch.
There! Finished!
You're now protected
from the evil gods of sickness.
All done, Azami.
You're free to go.
[Azami groans softly]
[gasps, sighs]
[MAN 1] Poor kid.
Watched her mother get beheaded.
Damn Kagemoris will pay
for what they did to us.
Mr. Yama, are you safe?
You weren't shadowed
by the Kagemoris, were you?
[YAMA] No. Someone was trying
near the base of the mountain,
but I shook them.
Goes to show
we should've been proactive.
If we already had
our hands on Seal,
this would've gone different.
It's just one boy's life.
It wasn't worth letting
the Kagemoris roll over us.
-[YAMA] Five bandits.
-[all gasp]
You think we haven't tried?
We sent five of our
most elite bandits after him,
and all of them wound up
with an arrow in the neck
or a blade in their ribs.
He's skilled enough
to shoot a pheasant
straight out of the air.
A human may
as well be a snail.
You lot wouldn't have stood
a chance against him.
[all sigh]
At minimum,
you'd need to take a hostage
so you'd have something on him.
[IVAN] Good idea.
-[slashing]
-[TSUGAIS] Uh?
[YAMA] Uh?
What?
[both gasp]
[Yama screams]
Higashi Village!
Good to see you!
[Yama yells]
What's going on with my body?
[gasps] I know you!
You're that pervert!
That's so rude.
I'm Ivan Yosano,
not some common pervert.
-What's happening?
-Is he holding something?
Oh, you can't see
my daemons, can you?
[men groaning]
[IVAN] Great.
That makes my job easy.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
[IVAN] Look at you.
You look like Asa.
[SHINGO] Ivan, you're up.
[OSHIRASAMA] Shall we stop
by the rest area?
[KYOKA] Yuru needs you,
so get outta here.
EPISODE 13
DAIKYO AND SHOKYO